

About Me: I'm Riann (pronounced Ryan).

I am an experienced teacher of 15 years, currently completing a program pursuing a Colorado elementary teaching license with the Friends Teacher Preparation Program. I am dedicated to building inclusive and equitable relationships with students, parents, and colleagues to create an engaging and collaborative learning environment that contributes to each child's success.

Professional Experience

Boulder Country Day School – Third Grade Gunbarrel, CO Teacher Candidate – Friends School Teacher Preparation Program

Aug 2018 - May 2019

- Planned and implemented a thematic unit about the Boulder County Watershed.
- Used reflective analysis of instructional strategies to create intentional and engaging lessons, creating interactive learning opportunities for each child.

Treehouse Learning, LLC

Lead Teacher & Preschool Lead Aug 2009 – July 2018

Louisville, CO

- Nine years of teaching experience with an average of 27 students aged between 3 and 5 years old.
- Researched, designed, and implemented innovative and engaging lesson plans and activities that developed intellectual, physical, and social/emotional learning.
- Successfully improved student participation in the classroom through integration of creative role-playing exercises.
- Implemented project-based learning, allowing students to become better self-learners.
- Planned, implemented, monitored, and assesd student development through individual observations and documentation.
- Created individualized goal sheets to differentiate and scaffold children's learning and document progress.
- Developed reciprocal, culturally responsive relationships with families and community to improve communication and trust between teachers, students, and parents.
- Acted as a liaison between teaching teams and administration to maintain policies, solve problems, and improve curriculum.
- Trained and mentored diverse teaching teams with successful outcomes in classroom management, behavior management, and curriculum focused strategies.

Peace of Mind Early Education

Lead Teacher & Program Coordinator

Woodbury, MN

Sep 2000 - Apr 2001, July 2001 - Oct 2002, Sep 2005 - Aug 2009

- Several years of teaching experience with an average of 14 students aged between 3 and 5 years old.
- Team mentor for training and guidance of classroom activities.

Hillsborough Kids Inc.

Family Services Counselor & Care Manager Oct 2002 – Aug 2005

Tampa, FL

oora)

- Crisis intervention, counseling, and protective supervision for children (aged 0 to 18 years).
- Researched, developed, and implemented case plans for families in the child welfare system.

Developmental Learning Center

Assistant Teacher Apr 2001 – Jul 2001

Education

B.A. Psychology (2000) University of Wisconsin–Stout

Colorado Early Childhood Teacher Qualification (2010) Front Range Community College

Yoga Alliance Certified Yoga Teacher (2018)

Breathe for Change–Denver

SMART-1 (Stress Management and Relaxation Techniques in Education) (2018) Colorado State University

Colorado Initial Teacher License (2019)

Friends Teacher Preparation Program

M.A. Learning, Development, and Family Sciences (expected August 2020)

University of Colorado-Denver

Concentration in Human Learning and Development